Annette Kolodny papers, 1968-[ongoing]
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Annette Kolodny papers, 1968-[ongoing]
MS 361
Kolodny, Annette, 1941-
This archive contains documents from Annette Kolodny's professional career from 1970 to the present. Included is teaching material from various universities, correspondence, speeches, presentations, research, drafts, manuscripts and publications, as well as legal documents relating to Kolodny's sexual and religious discrimination suit against the University of New Hampshire.
21 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Annette Kolodny received her Ph.D. from the University of California, Berkeley in 1969. Kolodny focused on American Literature.
She has taught at various universities throughout the United States and Canada.
While at the University of British Columbia (1970-1974), Kolodny was instrumental in creating a Women's Studies program, the first academically accredited Women's Studies program in Canada. This program became a model for both the United States and Canada.
Kolodny was an associate and assistant professor at the University of New Hampshire (1974-1979). She taught courses in American Literature and Women's Studies.
While teaching at the University of New Hampshire, Kolodny was involved in a sexual and religious discrimination suit, one of the earliest Title VII suits. This suit was settled out of court in October 1980, and from the financial award Kolodny founded the National Women's Studies Association Task Force on Academic Discrimination.
While at the University of Maryland (1982-1983) and Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI) (1983-1988), Kolodny taught American Literature.
Annette Kolodny came to the University of Arizona in 1988 and was Dean of Humanities from 1988-1993. She is currently a professor of Comparative Cultural and Literary Studies.
Kolodny has received awards from the Guggenheim, Rockefeller, and Ford Foundations, and a fellowship from the National Endowment for the Humanities.
She is the author of three books, The Lay of the Land: metaphor as experience and history in American life and letters(1975), The Land Before Her: fantasy and experience of the American frontiers, 1630-1860 (1984), and Failing the Future: A Dean looks at higher education in the 21st century (1998). Kolodny continues to publish actively in feminist literary criticism, eco-feminism, and feminist frontier studies.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
Series 1: Professional Career, 1970-1988
Series 2: Professional Activities, 1970s-1997
Series 3: Manuscripts and Publications, 1969-1985
Series 4: Legal, 1973-1984
Scope and Content Note
Series 1, Professional Career, contains material related to her teaching from 1970 to 1988. It includes teaching material, handouts, reading lists, syllabi, and class projects. This series has four sub-series: University of British Columbia, University of New Hampshire, University of Maryland, and Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI).
Series 2, Professional Activities, contains material related to her professional life from 1970 to the present. This series has six sub-series: Associations, Conferences, Grants, Reading Drafts, Recommendations, and Research.
Series 3, Manuscripts and Publications, contains materials relating to her Ph.D. dissertation, and two of her books, The Lay of the Land: metaphor as experience and history in American life and letters, and The Land Before Her: fantasy and experience of the American frontiers, 1630-1860. The Land Before Her files contain various drafts and edits, reviews, and correspondence relating to these publications. This series has 3 sub-series: Ph.D Dissertation, The Lay of the Land, and The Land before Her.
Series 4, Legal, contains materials relating to her sexual and religious discrimination suit against the University of New Hampshire. This series has seven sub-series: Correspondence, Depositions, Legal Fund, News Clippings, Promotion & Tenure, Student Evaluations, and Trial Material.
Access Terms
Kolodny, Annette, 1941-
University of Maryland, College Park
Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute
University of New Hampshire -- Trials, litigation, etc.
Authors, American -- 20th century
Educators -- United States -- 20th century
Ecocriticism
Ecofeminism
Women's studies
Sex discrimination against women
Container List
- Series 1: Professional Career, 1970-1988
  - Subseries 1: University of British Columbia, ca.1969-1974
    - UBC--Course Proposal, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - UBC--Course Proposal, Women's Studies (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - UBC--Course Proposal, Women's Studies (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - UBC--Lectures, Women's Studies (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - UBC--Lectures, Women's Studies (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - UBC--Lectures, Women's Studies (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - UBC--Women's Studies (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - UBC--Women's Studies, "Women in Literature" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: University of New Hampshire, ca.1974-1979
    - UNH--Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - UNH--American History and Culture--reading list (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - UNH--American Literature and Culture-- bibliography (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - UNH--American Literature and Culture--handouts (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - UNH--American Literature and Culture--teaching material (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - UNH--American Literature and Culture--teaching material (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - UNH--American Women Writers, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - UNH--American Women Writers, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - UNH--Feminist Literary Criticism (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - UNH--Major Women Writers, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - UNH--Major Women Writers, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - UNH--Puritanism and Enlightenment--lectures, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - UNH--Puritanism and Enlightenment--teaching material, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - UNH--Puritanism and Enlightenment--teaching material (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - UNH--Radical Literature (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - UNH--Special Studies in American Literature (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - UNH--Special Studies in American Literature (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - UNH--Special Studies in American Literature (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - UNH--Survey of American Literature--teaching material (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - UNH--Teaching Material--various (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - UNH--Teaching Material--various (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - UNH--Teaching Material--various (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - UNH--Theory and Method of Literary Criticism, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - UNH--Women's Studies, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3: University of Maryland, 1980-1983
    - University of Maryland--American Renaissance, Fall 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - University of Maryland--Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - University of Maryland--Critical Methods--teaching material, Fall 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - University of Maryland--Critical Methods--teaching material, Spring 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - University of Maryland--Short Story, Spring 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - University of Maryland--Women in Literature, Fall 1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - University of Maryland--Women in Literature, Spring 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI), 1983-1988
    - RPI--America Against Itself, Spring 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - RPI--American Fiction II--teaching material, Spring 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - RPI--American Fiction II--teaching material, Spring 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - RPI--American Fiction II--teaching material, Spring 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - RPI--American Renaissance--teaching material (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - RPI--American Writers and Cultural Change, Fall 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - RPI--American Writers and Cultural Change, Fall 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - RPI--American Writers and Cultural Change, Fall 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - RPI--American Writers and Cultural Change, Fall 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - RPI--Articles on Carol Gilligan, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - RPI--Bibliography Cards (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - RPI--Bibliography Cards (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - RPI--Bibliography Cards (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - RPI--Bibliography Cards (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - RPI--Bibliography of Gender and Science (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - RPI--Bibliography, Research, and the Publication of Criticism, Spring 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - RPI--Class handouts (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - RPI--Class handouts (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - RPI--Class Lectures (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - RPI--Class Lectures (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - RPI--Class Lectures (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - RPI--Contemporary Literature, Spring 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - RPI--Film and Tapes (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - RPI--Independent Study, Fall 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - RPI--The Novel, Fall 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - RPI--Textual Research and Scholarly Criticism, Fall 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - RPI--Women Studies, Spring 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - RPI--Women Studies (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - RPI--Women Studies (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - RPI--Women Writers--Correspondence, Fall 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - RPI--Women Writers--Teaching Material, Fall 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - RPI--Women Writers, Fall 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - RPI--Women Writers, Fall 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Correspondence, January-August 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Correspondence, September 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Correspondence, October-December 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Final Report, March 19, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Preliminary Report, January 1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Results of Inspection and Final Report, April 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Site Inspections, October 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Reports, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Final report, comments, summary, January 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Study of modification to HVAC system, January 1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - RPI--Russell Sage Laboratory--Final Report, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Series 2: Professional Activities, 1970-1997
  - Subseries 1: Associations, ca.1982-1992
    - Associations--Advanced Placement Council, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Associations--ASA (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Associations--CSW (Commission on Status of Women) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Associations--CSW (Commission of the Status of Women) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Associations--FIPSE, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Associations--FIPSE, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Associations--National Society of Arts and Letters, Tucson Chapter, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Associations--NWSA--task force part 1, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Associations--NWSA--task force part 2, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Associations--NWSA--task force part 3, 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Associations--Pandora's Press--Correspondence, February 1982-June 12, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Associations--Pandora's Press--Correspondence, June 15, 1982-August 27, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Associations--Pandora's Press--Correspondence, August 28, 1982-Decemeber 1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Associations--Pandora's Press--Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Associations--Pandora's Press--Correspondence, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Associations--Teachers for a Democratic Culture, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Conferences, ca.1973-1997
    - Conferences--ALA, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Conferences--Alpha Gamma Delta Sorority, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Conferences--Arizona Humanities Day, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Conferences--ASA (American Studies Association), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Conferences--ASA (American Studies Association), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Conferences--ASA (American Studies Association), 1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Conferences--ASA (American Studies Association), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Conferences--ASECS, Panel on Crevecoeur, April 5-9, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Conferences--ASU Grads Scholar Conference, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Conferences--AWF Panel "Political Correctness" 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Conferences--CCCC Convention, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Conferences--Colorado, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Conferences--Crete Conference, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Conferences--Dean's Conference, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Conferences--Early American Literature Conference, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Conferences--Gender and American Culture Series, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Conferences--Humanities Institute, Fall 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Conferences--Michigan Department of Education Conference, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Conferences--MLA, Executive Committee, 1984-1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Conferences--MLA, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Conferences--MLA, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Conferences--MLA (San Diego), December 27-30, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Conferences--National Humanities Center, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Conferences--NEH, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Conferences--New Jersey Project Conference, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Conferences-- NWSA, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Conferences-- NWSA, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Conferences-- NWSA, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Conferences-- NWSA, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Conferences-- NWSA, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Conferences--RPI, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Conferences--Skidmore Millay Symposium, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Conferences--University of Akron (Ohio), March 1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Conferences--University of Central Florida, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Conferences--University of Montana (cancelled), March 1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Conferences--University of Nebraska, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Conferences--University of Northern Colorado, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Conferences--Western Humanities Conference, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Conferences--Western Kentucky University, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Conferences--Western Women Conference, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Conferences--Women's Studies Colloquium, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 3: Grants, ca.1975-1988
    - Grants--AAUW Fellowship, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Grants--ACLS, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Grants--Ford Foundation, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Grants--Ford Foundation, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Grants--Guggenheim, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Grants--Guggenheim, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Grants--NEH, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Grants--Rockefeller Foundation, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Grants--Rockefeller Foundation, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Grants--RPI Information (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 4: Reading Drafts, ca.1976-1996
    - Reading Draft--"American Studies: Past & Future," 1990 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Reading Draft--"American Studies & Women's Studies," 1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Reading Draft--"Anti-Feminist Harassment," 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Reading Draft--"Breaking the Prairie Wolf Code," by Lavonne Mueller, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Reading Draft--"Captive Women..." 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Reading Draft--"Critical Models as Tools and Tribulations," 1976 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Reading Draft--"Dancing Between Left & Right..." 1987 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Reading Draft--"Dancing Through the Mine-fields..." 1979 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Reading Draft--"Dancing Through the Mine Fields..." 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Reading Draft--"Feminist Criticism in the 21st Century," 1991 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Reading Draft--"Feminism in the U.S. Academy," (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Reading Draft--"Family-Friendly Campus in a Family-Friendly World," 1996 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Reading Draft--"From Lawsuit to Dean," 1988 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Reading Draft--"Gender Interpretation of Literary Texts," 1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Reading Draft--"Imagining the Frontier: Gender and Landscape," 1989 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Reading Draft--"Influence of Anxiety," 1985 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Reading Draft--"The Integrity of Memory," 1985 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Reading Draft--"Language and Gender," 1979 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Reading Draft--"Literature and Literacy," 1988 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Reading Draft--"Margaret Atwood," (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Reading Draft--"Margaret Fuller," 1983 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Reading Draft--"Margaret Fuller and Rhetoric," 1993 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Reading Draft--"MLA Panel: Gleaning from Women's Archival Material," 1981 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Reading Draft--"The New American Adam and Eve," 1982 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Reading Draft--"The New Jersey Project Conference," 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Reading Draft--NWSA Journal, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Reading Draft--NWSA, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Reading Draft--"Patterns of Pluralism..." (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Reading Draft--"Policies and Strategies for Family Care," (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Reading Draft--"Raising Standards while Lowering Anxiety," 1990-1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Reading Draft--"Raising Standards while Lowering Anxiety," 1990-1996 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Reading Draft--"Reconfiguring the Narratives of First Contact," 1996 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Reading Draft--"The Relationship of Women's Studies," 1983 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Reading Draft--"The Rocky Road to Tenure and Promotion for Women," 1994 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Reading Draft--"Setting an Agenda for Change," 1993 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Reading Draft--"Still Dancing Through the Mine-fields," 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Reading Draft--"Women in Administration," 1992 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Reading Draft--"Women in Veterinary Academia," 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Reading Draft--"Women Studies," 1983 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5: Recommendations
    - Recommendations (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Recommendations (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Recommendations (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Recommendations (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Recommendations (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Recommendations--Job Search (personal) (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Recommendations--Job Search (personal) (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Recommendations--Vitas (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Recommendations--Vitas (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Recommendations--Vitas (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 6: Research, ca.1993
    - Research--Humanities (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Research--Humanities (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Research--"Setting Agenda for Change in Academia," 1993 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Research--"Setting Agenda for Change in Academia," 1993 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Research--"Setting Agenda for Change in Academia," 1993 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Research--Women's Studies--papers (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Research--Women's Studies--papers (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Research--Women's Studies--articles (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Research--Women's Studies--articles (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Research--Women's Studies--clippings (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Research--Women's Studies--reports (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Manuscripts and Publications, 1968-1986
  - Subseries 1: Ph.D Dissertation, ca. 1968
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--Prospectus, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--completed draft, chapter1 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--completed draft, chapter 2-3 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--completed draft, chapter 4 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--completed Xerox copy, chapter 1 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--completed Xerox copy, chapter 2-3 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation--completed Xerox copy, chapter 4-end (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2: The Lay of the Land
    - The Lay of the Land--Orignal typed manuscript, front matter/chapters 1-2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - The Lay of the Land--Original typed manuscript, front matter/chapters 3 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - The Lay of the Land--Orignal typed manuscript, front matter/chapters 4 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - The Lay of the Land--Orignal typed manuscript, front matter/chapters 5 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - The Lay of the Land--Reviews (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: The Land before Her, ca. 1975-1986
    - The Land before Her--Original manuscript, edited, front matter-p.80 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - The Land before Her--Original manuscript, edited, P.81-212 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - The Land before Her--Original manuscript, edited, P.213-343 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - The Land before Her--Original manuscript, edited, P.344-454 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - The Land before Her--Original manuscript, edited, P.455-559 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Land before Her--Final typed manuscript, chapters 1-2 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - The Land before Her--Final typed manuscript, chapters 3-5 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - The Land before Her--Final typed manuscript, chapters 6-7 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - The Land before Her--Final typed manuscript, chapters 8-10 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - The Land before Her--Final typed manuscript, epilogue (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - The Land before Her--Final typescript, chapters 1-2 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - The Land before Her--Final typescript, chapters 3-5 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - The Land before Her--Final typescript, chapters 6-7 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - The Land before Her--Final typescript, chapters 8-10 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - The Land before Her--Final typescript, epilogue (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - The Land before Her--Galleys, part 1 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - The Land before Her--Galleys, part 2 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - The Land before Her--Correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - The Land before Her--Correspondence, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - The Land before Her--Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - The Land before Her--Epigraphs / Permission (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Reviews (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Reviews (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Reviews (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Textual changes (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Series 4: Legal, 1970-1984
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, ca. 1970-1983
    - Correspondence, 1970-1983 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence--Acceptance to UNH, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence--Anti-Semitism, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence--Client/Lawyer, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence--Client/Lawyer, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence--Client/Lawyer, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence--Client/Lawyer, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence--Client/Lawyer, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), July, 1975-October, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), November, 1976-July 1978 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), August, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), February 3, 1979-March 7, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), March 8, 1979-April 30, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), May 2, 1979-October 12, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), October 17, 1979-January 9, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence--Legal (Lawyer/Client), January 16, 1980-February 15, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 5)